Somewhere, somehow, someone's going to pay.
Commando is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Mark L. Lester.
John Matrix, the former leader of a special commando strike force that always got the toughest
jobs done, is forced back into action when his young daughter is kidnapped.
To find her, Matrix has to fight his way through an array of punks, killers,
one of his former commandos, and a fully equipped private army.
With the help of a feisty stewardess and an old friend, Matrix has only a few hours to
overcome his greatest challenge: finding his daughter before she's killed.
John Matrix, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Cindy, played by Rae Dawn Chong.
Arius, played by Dan Hedaya.
Bennett, played by Vernon Wells.
Major General Franklin Kirby, played by James Olson.
Sully, played by David Patrick Kelly.
Commando is a 1985 American action film directed by Mark L.
Lester and produced by Joel Silver.
It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger in the lead role, alongside Rae Dawn
Chong, Alyssa Milano, Vernon Wells, Bill Duke and Dan Hedaya.
The musical score was composed by James Horner.
Commando was released in the United States on October 4, 1985, where
it received praise for the action sequences and humor.
The film became a commercial success at the box office and was nominated for a
Saturn Award for Best Special Effects, but lost to Back to the Future.
The film explores themes of daughter, fight, kidnapping, mercenary, lone wolf.
The tone is intense.